<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-15T21:08:08-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Experts should curate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/16/curation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Experts should curate" /><published>2020-08-16T12:01:44-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-16T12:01:44-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/16/curation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/16/curation.html">&lt;p&gt;You ever want to learn something, and just get totally overwhelmed by the near infinite number of guides out there? &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-from-the-internet&quot;&gt;Learning from the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re an early-career designer who wanted to depeen their understanding of typography, what do you do? Plugging “how to get better at typography” into Google returns a deluge of mediocre “content” from SaaS company blogs. Eventually, you read enough of these guides to understand the components of type usage: font choice &amp;amp; pairings, size scale, accessibility, etc. Then, you make your queries more specific and find the best guide on each topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the process of learning anything on the internet. There are several metaskills at work here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knowing what to search for&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decomposing your need into different steps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knowing which guide to follow for each step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tricky thing is that most of these skills are catch-22s. How do you know to search for when you don’t know what you’re supposed to learn? How do you decompose a problem into steps when you don’t understand a problem? How do you know what the best guide is for each step when you don’t know how that step works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I’ve lost track of the number of times I’ve said to myself “I’m going to learn how to build a basic CRUD app this weekend” only to lose the entire two days wading through an ocean of guides without writing any code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many domains of craft like product design and software engineering (though I can’t speak as well to the latter), there’s already a ton of great guides out there for most things you’d want to learn&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The real problem is figuring out which ones to follow. If we want to increase the amount of knowledge in the world, the marginal unit of expert time is better spent organizing than producing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;knowledge-maps-out-there-today&quot;&gt;Knowledge maps out there today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One great example of this is &lt;em&gt;Khan Academy’s knowledge map of K–12 math&lt;/em&gt;, now defunct, alas. Having an authoritative source map out the knowledge space and their dependencies + provide a good resource to learn it means that a lot of the metawork outlined above is done for learners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;blogImage&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blogImg/curation/knowledgeMap.png&quot; alt=&quot;khan academy knowledge map&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Khan academy knowledge map of K-12 math. Now deprecated 😢.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, K-12 math today is not too different from where it was 10 years ago. So a map of knowledge here has limited utility compared to domains that are rapidly changing like software engineering, where the canonical way of doing something today is often radically different than 10 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another drawback of this map is that it only links to first party content. Sal Khan is an amazing educator, but is he better than the rest of the Internet combined?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addressing exactly the above two is the &lt;em&gt;Open Source Society University&lt;/em&gt; – most well known for their &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science&quot;&gt;open source computer science curriculum&lt;/a&gt;. It works like the name says: the whole thing is a github read.me that anyone can contribute to (though in practice, there seems to be only 1-2 maintainers), describing a computer science syllabus where all the content is from free 3rd parties sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;blogImage&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blogImg/curation/ossu.png&quot; alt=&quot;OSSU&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Screenshot of the OSSU curriculum&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While an improvement over some dimensions, this approach still leaves much to be desired in the following aspects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maintenance cost&lt;/em&gt; There are only &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ossu/computer-science/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;~1.5 contributors&lt;/a&gt;. We need 100x more if we want to tend a truly comprehensive garden of knowledge for any topic. How do we motivate them? For a deep dive on the people who work on open source, I recommend picking up the book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Working-Public-Making-Maintenance-Software/dp/0578675862&quot;&gt;Working in Public&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modularity of content&lt;/em&gt; Probably a downstream consequence of lacking maintainers, but almost all sections of OSSU lead to full EDX style courses. This is not particularly useful for the most common mode of Internet learning: picking up only the exact knowledge necessary to unblock yourself on a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Connecting the dots&lt;/em&gt; How does the knowledge from one course relate to the next? This gets especially tricky when the material is cobbled together from 3rd party sources that don’t talk to each other. Having even a 5% gap in coverage between modules can send learners down a rabbit hole that exhausts their motivation. This problem gets worse when you start making content more modular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-even-better-knowledge-map&quot;&gt;An even better knowledge map&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the lessons from KA and OSSU, how do you make a better knowledge map?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comprehensive and detailed syllabus of knowledge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Third party, to leverage the Internet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Granular, so you can drill into a specific topic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comprehensive, so you can situate yourself within the domain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discussion of source material&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For different kinds of learners (video vs text vs project) with different kinds of prereqs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discuss how they relate to prereqs. Fill in any gaps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Community of maintainers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To keep expading the graph, and updating content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To Identify areas with weaker coverage, and call for writers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could boostrap the first two for a while, but will eventually need to find a solution to the community problem – whether in an open source way, or by forming a company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, a knowledge map on its own is not useful unless people are active deriving value from it and the answer to the community problem will entirely depend on who derives value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Mostly true for fundamental topics. There’s obviously not enough documentation at the edges of any domain, but most people are not there, and the people who are are better equipped with the metaskills needed to help themselves. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You ever want to learn something, and just get totally overwhelmed by the near infinite number of guides out there?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Short note on grace</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/16/grace.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Short note on grace" /><published>2020-08-16T12:01:44-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-16T12:01:44-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/16/grace</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/16/grace.html">&lt;p&gt;In different period of my life, I paid attention to different kinds of character traits. These days, it’s grace. But hadn’t always been.&lt;!--more--&gt;  When I was in my early career, I was particularly drawn to ambition. I read all the PG essays, idolized the early YC founders. I believed that ambition was 80% of the reason behind any success. It was the trait that lead to enormous risk appetites, and fueled the grit and creativity to satiate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still love ambition, but lately, I’ve also become far more attuned to the presence of grace and the people who carry it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definining grace is tricky. We often use it casually use it to mean beauty. That’s not what I’m interested in. The version I like is closer to the Christian definition, which is “free and unmerited favour that God gave to humanity by sending Jesus to die”. I think the first time I became aware of Grace was in my senior year of college. My seatmate Louisa spotted me reading Khalil Gibran in a particularly boring business school class and invited me to her Bible study group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was kind of an ass. I was sleeping in an unheated basement in Canada, stressed from running a startup, and dealing with a heavy courseload. Each night I went to their study group, I asked a ton of super skeptical questions – all of which they answered in good faith. Never trying to convert me. Just answering my questions as best they could. They even invited me to sleep over on their couch when they discovered my questionable sleeping arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until much later that I had come to understand what they exibited as grace. I think if I have to describe it in my own words, it’s when you are good only because it is the right thing to do. Grace is a stronger version of nice, a more private version of generosity, a more intrinsict version charity. It’s in some ways the opposite of justice – which is about dealing to each what they deserve. Grace is when you believe in each person’s inherent worth in all cicumstances, and act according to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, graceful is now the highest level of compliment I give.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In different period of my life, I paid attention to different kinds of character traits. These days, it’s grace. But hadn’t always been.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Being negatively-driven</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/07/negative-drive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Being negatively-driven" /><published>2020-08-07T22:43:44-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-07T22:43:44-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/07/negative-drive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/07/negative-drive.html">&lt;p&gt;For as long as I remember, I’ve derived much of my force of will from negativity: feeling not smart enough, watching my peers be more successful, not having gone to a famous college&lt;!--more--&gt;, having done a professional bootcamp, competing with coworkers (secretly!), being an alien in an anti-immigrant country, and a million other nothings that find their way on my shoulder and stay there to become chips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends are the same – absurdly driven by a sense of not being enough. One of them almost comically so. The guy had a blue light lamp on his desk pointed to his face to keep him awake so he can work longer hours. (Love you Mike, but you’re gonna die young). Maybe this is a Canadian thing. Always being in the shadow of the US can really give you a complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always know that this was unhealthy. Obviously, wouldn’t it be nice if I could have the same drive to do things, but also be more happy? Of course I’d want to change this. But it’s hard for several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most obviously, this &lt;em&gt;negativity fuel really works&lt;/em&gt;. I’m a high level designer at a pretty famous tech company where I work daily with people whose work I grew up looking up to. And this job provides me financial comfort in the most expensive city in the world. By all accounts, this is what young Yitong would have considered a successful life. Why mess with the source of my willfullness when being willfull has given me success and, because of that, now constitutes a large part of my identity. What if in doing away with the negativity, I also lose some of the drive? Would I even want to be happier, but less driven?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the guilt that I feel when I try to think too deeply about this. Even as I’m writing this, I can hear my inner voice saying “do you think [insert successful friend] is wasting time on thoughts like this? They’re working on their next thing while you’re wallowing in self-doubt. Move on already!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A slightly more rational rephrasing of the same thought could be: what if the solution is to fake it ‘till you make it? Maybe you just have convince yourself that the negativity is not a problem until it really isn’t anymore. Certainly a lot of life works this way, so why wouldn’t this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this last one is silly, but I just can’t get over the aesthetics of the solution space, which is often tinged with an orientalist worship of meditation, and adjacent to weird Tim Ferris-style productivity-guru-ism. Conversely, I also like the aesthetics of the negativity-driven energy. Wearing all the chips on my shoulder makes feel like the underdog or an outsider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe six months of quarantine has made me feel listless too many Fridays in a row. Maybe work kinda sucks right now. Maybe I have this shiny new blog that needs content. Whatever it is, I’ve decided to try to talk about and process these feelings in public, much like Ankit has done with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ankit.fyi/being-alone&quot;&gt;loneliness&lt;/a&gt;, and Laura with with &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldeming.posthaven.com/how-not-to-be-sad&quot;&gt;sadness&lt;/a&gt;. Solving this problem now is valuable to me because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Negative energy is brittle&lt;/em&gt;. You can accumulate so much of it that you get bent out of shape over silly things. It’s also a poor source of energy when you are dealing with hardship in life (and since it’s COVID times, we’re all dealing with hardhships 24/7).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Negative energy is less creative&lt;/em&gt; It really gets you going when what needs doing is clear, and the challenge is in the execution, but lately the problems I face have shifted from doing to figuring out what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Happiness is worth investing in&lt;/em&gt; I’ve never prioritized my own happiness because it felt more important to do great things. But I’m starting to think that being happy will unlock a new frontier of things that I would otherwise not be able to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no solution here, but laying out the problem statement is a start to what I hope is a series of posts digging deeper into my negative energy, and turning that around.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For as long as I remember, I’ve derived much of my force of will from negativity: feeling not smart enough, watching my peers be more successful, not having gone to a famous college</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rebuilding my site in the open pt.1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/newblog1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rebuilding my site in the open pt.1" /><published>2020-07-24T22:43:44-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-24T22:43:44-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/newblog1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/24/newblog1.html">&lt;p&gt;I haven’t updated my personal website since late 2017 – probably the longest period ever between two redesigns. It’s held up well for over 4 years, but it’s time for a refresh.&lt;!--more--&gt; I have several motivations for this latest effort. First, I’m writing more so I’d like a blog-first design, something that can be a permanent home for my thoughts on the internet for decades to come. Second, I’m itching to write more code lately, and Jekyll is a pretty low friction way of getting back into. Lastly, I’ve been toying around with the idea of building a Notion-driven Jekyll competitor, so I figured that before embarking on that, I’d make at least a serious attempt at building something on Jekyll to see where it performs well and where it falls short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something else that I’d like to experiment with is designing this site directly in code. I’ve done this on some smaller projects before, but never tried it on anything of this level, so it should be fun. I have a general idea of where I’d like to go with the design, but am planning on figuring most of it out as I go. As a result, I expect this site to be pretty janky while it is under construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up, getting rid of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/minima&quot;&gt;Minima&lt;/a&gt; in order to roll my own theme. Things are gonna look pretty barebones to start with, but I’m exciting to get something out there. After a few hours of noodling around, I got myself set up with a pretty basic site from scratch – it’s barely designed at all, but at least the typography no longer hurts my eyes. I went with Colfax and a bit of IBM Plex, the former because it was a typeface I had already paid for, and the latter for dates and, at least aspirationally, code snippets. I’d like to buy something more fun from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.futurefonts.xyz/&quot;&gt;Future Fonts&lt;/a&gt; later, but I’ve got to figure out the baseline for the rest of the site before letting myself fall down the type rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, I really appreciate foundries like &lt;a href=&quot;https://processtypefoundry.com/help/base/how-many-domains-can-use-the-fonts/&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/a&gt; that issue licenses allowing for usage on multiple domains. It’s nice to have a small roster of fonts that can be easily used on small projects. Typekit used to serve this purpose for me, but I’ve grown to hate the subscription fee lately. I’d much rather pay the maker of the product directly and own the license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time, I’d like to put up a work section covering the projects I’ve done. Might also look into an image layout so that I can stick a couple of pictures up on my about page.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I haven’t updated my personal website since late 2017 – probably the longest period ever between two redesigns. It’s held up well for over 4 years, but it’s time for a refresh.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The structure of progress in craft</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/03/craft-progress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The structure of progress in craft" /><published>2020-06-03T10:58:44-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-03T10:58:44-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/03/craft-progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/03/craft-progress.html">&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of research on the structure of progress in science (Kuhn, Popper, Deutsch, etc.) but what about the progress of professional craft?&lt;!--more--&gt; How do we get better at programming, design, furniture building, cooking, entrepreneurship, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by the way, if these fields feel like they are unrelated, you’re right. Cooking is not the same as entrepreneurship. That’s why great cooks are not automatically great restauranteurs. But I’d like to suggest that both fields have a lot of commonality in their epistemology. The process of getting better might be surprisingly similar across all these professions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these professions do advance, some faster than others. Most obvious in programming. The default answer is that the tools are getting better, but that’s not the only thing. Even if it was, we’re still far from understanding how tools get better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because Figma is better than Illustrator for product design does not automatically make you a better designer. You need process knowledge, understanding of history, a community of practitioners, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, we don’t even have a reasonable list of inputs into good craft. Here are some questions I’d like to better understand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the constraining factors on tooling improvement? For example, why did tooling grow far more quickly in programming than product design?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What about the more subjective part of craft? What is beautiful design? What is elegant code? How do our tools internalize and shape subjective practices?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better understanding of craft would yield great societal dividends. Most people are engaged on a day to day in activities that look more like craft than science.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">There’s a lot of research on the structure of progress in science (Kuhn, Popper, Deutsch, etc.) but what about the progress of professional craft?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Design tools and design jobs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/25/tools-jobs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design tools and design jobs" /><published>2020-02-25T09:58:44-08:00</published><updated>2020-02-25T09:58:44-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/25/tools-jobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/25/tools-jobs.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the last 2 decades, we went from photoshop to sketch to figma, but these are all fundamentally tools for drawing boxes. Where is the Engelbart-esque software for designers?&lt;!--more--&gt; Why has no one implemented any of Bret Victor’s demos? Why is design tooling so stale, and what are the ways forward?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What drove each major tooling evolution?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photoshop: 2000 – 2014&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2000: Apple introduces Aqua UI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2008: iOS app store opens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2009: Dribbble launches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job of tools: flex your craftsmanship&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sketch: 2014 – 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2013: Apple introduces iOS 7&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2014: Google introduces Material Design.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2014: Sketch 3 released&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job of tools: cheap, accessible way to produce simple UI elements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sketch to Figma: 2018 – beyond&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2018: Airbnb designers start talking about their internal collaboration tooling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2019: Scaled design teams outside of Google, Facebook, and Airbnb emerge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The job of tools: enable teams to work together faster and more seamlessly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, business needs drive job description, which in turn drive tooling requirements. Each major tooling followed a redefinition of the role of design to respond to a new business context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s our best guess for the evolution of design tools? Here’s an overview of what people are working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produce design options faster: since 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problem: manually doing visual combinatorics is too slow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solution: Parametric / declarative design tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example: Jon Gold’s declarative design tool demo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example: Grasshopper, a parametric design tool from architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make it easier to work on complex systems: since 2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problem: problems are getting more complex. Our brains are not getting faster&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solution: decompose and visualize complex problems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example: bret victor’s entire body of work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduce the distance between creator and creation: since 1996&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problem: the longer the feedback loop for each iteration, the slower / worse the outcome&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solution: eliminate steps between idea and code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example: Airbnb’s wireframe to react demo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example: Webflow aka wysiwyg HTML + CSS editor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example: literally a dozendemoofdrawingto vector design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are definitely real problems that designers experience,  but why haven’t we seen any runaway successes? One answer is that they don’t map to the high value parts of a designer’s job description. Gasp! Is the implication that improving designers’ ability to produce a lot of great design solutions to complex problems… is actually not super valuable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you argue that when that’s literally what designers spend most of their day doing? I think the answer is that our existing tooling is sufficiently good at helping us solve the problems we are asked to solve at the speed we are asked to solve them. How come?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the problems are becoming more obvious. Complexity has decreased, not increased as the greenfield ideas of this technological eras get picked clean and more and more startups win less from innovating, and more from operating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, our hardware devices have settled into a steady state, and so have the affordances, and in turn the interaction patterns. There is nothing more for screen-based interfaces after after the edge to edge screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, as patterns settle, users get used to them. The benefit of a novel and superior pattern is wiped out by the cost of deviating from user expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So could the ideas from the last section improve things at the margin? Yes, but the ceiling for improvement is too low to feed a new design tool company. You can see this in the last switch from Sketch to Figma: the actual drawing tool is virtually the same. There are improvements like vector networks and better typesetting features, but they are lost in the sea of praise for their collaboration features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the mistake of these retro-future ideas so far is that they started thinking from the designer’s job description, as opposed to the wider business context designers practice their profession. So what does the context of tomorrow look like and what kind of tools will we need to solve them? Here are some ideas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re in the early stages of design collaboration compared to software engineering. What can we learn from developers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highest leverage activities designers engage in are critique and reviews. How do you scale and accelerate these processes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be increasing overlap between PM and design. How do you bake more product tools into design tools?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have these super compelling demos, can we reverse into the job description for which they would make sense, and the hypothetical context in which these job descriptions would emerge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Produce design options faster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Job: iterate as fast as possible over a large visual solution space&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For this job to be valuable it must be true that: it is both difficult to manually find the best solution, and finding the best solution really matters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Circumstances enabling the above: brand design becomes a far more important function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make it easier to work on complex systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Job: navigate idea mazes faster&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For this job to be valuable it must be true that: there are deeply complex problems in design for which solutions are really hard to find&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Circumstances enabling the above: product + design converge into a single discipline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduce the distance between creator and creation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Job: empower designers to shift the entire speed &amp;lt;&amp;gt; fidelity frontier to the right&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For this job to be valuable it must be true that: you can reliably move the whole frontier, as opposed to just traveling along the tradeoff curve.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Circumstances enabling the above: better technology?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Over the last 2 decades, we went from photoshop to sketch to figma, but these are all fundamentally tools for drawing boxes. Where is the Engelbart-esque software for designers?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bridgewater culture</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/27/bridgewater.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bridgewater culture" /><published>2020-01-27T09:58:44-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-27T09:58:44-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/27/bridgewater</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/27/bridgewater.html">&lt;p&gt;Every org should try to be more like Bridgewater if they can pull it off.&lt;!--more--&gt; Radical transparency leads to better decision making, higher resource allocation efficiency, more meritocracy, and some really fun weird shit in the long run. It’s also incredibly hard to pull off, so most are better off not even trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 2 things you need to get right for this kinda org to work: a decision tracking system and the right culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s one theoretical example of the Dalio system working: an email marketing manager sends a re-engagement campaign with A, B, C variants in the headline. They predict that A is the most promising. A support agent predicts B instead based on their customer intuition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support analyst wins. Their correct prediction is logged on their profile. Next time, the email marketing manager will consult the support analyst. Better campaigns ensue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It gets more interesting when you also gate access to decision making on track record (as opposed to role and title). It’s been a year, this support agent is consistently on point in their predictions. They are now invited to decision making meetings higher up the chain, giving input into the email marketing yearly budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take this to the extreme, you get the unbundling of traditional jobs and levels. Each person’s role boundaries are determined purely by what they have a track record on. There are no more pre-defined jobs. People allocated their time and energy on problems they have advantage on, building a track record, and ladder into more and more high impact decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add some common record keeping standard and data portability, and you get massive labour market liquidity. Maybe you’ll even see the rise of micro-contracting, e.g. instead of having your pretty-good-support-agent do email marketing, you contract that decision making part to external workers with a track record on this decision in the top 1% percentile. Today, this is only possible for rote decisions where qualifying a worker’s competency is reliable and cheap aka transcriptions, translation, labeling — the MTurk tasks. The better you can assess decision competency, the more you outsource high impact and complexity problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With enough people with tracking standards floating around, you could run functional &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.p2pfoundation.net/Decentralized_Autonomous_Organization&quot;&gt;Decentralized Autonomous Organizations&lt;/a&gt;. So why aren’t we on this path? It requires some crazy skillful culture &amp;amp; org building. More on this next time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Every org should try to be more like Bridgewater if they can pull it off.</summary></entry></feed>